Register of the Sir Karl Raimund Popper Papers, 1928-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Sir Karl Raimund Popper papers
1928-1995
86039
Hoover Institution Archives
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, printed matter, phonotapes, phonorecords, and photographs, relating to philosophy, the nature of knowledge, the philosophy of culture, the philosophy and methodology of science, and the philosophy of history and the social sciences. Deacribed in two groups, original collection (boxes 1-463) and the incremental materials acquired at a later date (boxes 464-583).
575 manuscript boxes, 6 oversize boxes, 2 card file boxes, 28 envelopes, 47 phonotape reels, 4 phonotape cassettes, 11 phonorecords (248 linear feet)
Popper, Karl Raimund, Sir, 1902-
Access
Microfilm use only. Use copies of sound recordings are available for immediate use.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986 with increments added at a later date.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Collection available on microfilm. Original collection (473 reels) and Incremental materials (91 reels)
Biographical Note
1902, July 28 Born, Vienna, Austria
1926 Ph.D., University of Vienna
1930 Married Josefine Anne Henninger (1906-1985)
1934 Author, Logik der Forschung
1930-1935 Schoolteacher, Vienna
1937-1945 Senior Lecturer in Philosophy, Canterbury University College, University of New Zealand, Christchurch
1945 Author, The Open Society and Its Enemies
1945-1949 Reader in Logic and Scientific Method, London School of Economics and Political Science, University of London, England
1949-1969 Professor of Logic and Scientific Method, London School of Economics and Political Science, University of London
1954 Author, Miseria dello storicismo
1962 Author, Conjectures and Refutations: The Growth of Scientific Knowledge
1965 Knighted
1972 Author, Objective Knowledge: An Evolutionary Approach
1976 Author, Unended Quest: An Intellectual Autobiography
1977 Co-author (with John C. Eccles), The Self and Its Brain: An Argument for Interactionism
1979 Author, Die beiden Grundprobleme der Erkenntnistheorie
1982-1983 Author, Postscript to The Logic of Scientific Discovery
1983 Author, A Pocket Popper
1984 Author, Auf der Suche nach einer besseren Welt
1986- Head, Ludwig Boltzmann Institut fur Wissenschaftstheorie, Vienna
Scope and Content Note
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, printed matter, phonotapes, phonorecords, and photographs, relating to philosophy, the nature of knowledge, the philosophy of culture, the philosophy and methodology of science, and the philosophy of history and the social sciences. Most of collection also available on microfilm (564 reels). Sound use copies of sound recordings available.
Civilization--Philosophy.; Conservatism.; History--Philosophy.; Knowledge, Theory of.; Philosophers.; Philosophy.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Science--Methodology.; Science--Philosophy.; Social sciences--Philosophy.
- MICROFILM REEL CONTENT GUIDE
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS I, 1928-1986
  Scope and Contents note
  Conference papers, drafts of books, essays, notes, reviews, speeches, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically
  - Unidentified writings, n.d.
    - General (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - General (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
    - Fragments (Folder 16-24)
    - Fragments (Box 3, Folder 1-36)
    - Fragments (Box 459, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous pages (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "An Alternative Proof that Probability Is Now Ampliative," Holograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Animal Alphabet," Holograph and typescript (Folder 2)
  - "The Arrow of Time," Typescript of chapter for a book, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Axiom Definition," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "An Axiom System for Intuitionist Probability," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Axiome, Definitionen, und Postulate der Geometrie," Typescript (2 bound volumes) (Folder 6)
  - "Bemerkung zum komplementaritatsproblem der Quantenmechanik," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "Bemerkungen uber Sprachtheorie und ihre Geschichte," Holograph (Folder 8)
  - "Bemerkungen zum sogenannten Problem der Willensfreiheit," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - "Bleen is Projectible," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - "Bohr Copenhagen Interpretation," Typescript outline, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "Boole's Philosophy of Logic," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - "C-Axiom System," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "Can There Be a Quantum Logic?" Holograph, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "Cardinal Numbers in New Foundation," Holograph (Folder 15)
  - "Causal Completeness," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - "Causality," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - "Clouds, Clocks, and Organisms: An Essay on Causation and Propensity," Holograph outline (Folder 18)
  - "Comments on Quantum Mechanics," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - "The Construction of Shortest Random-Like Sequences of Degree n" (with L. R. B. Elton), Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "A Contradiction Between Special Relativity and the Copenhagen Interpretation of Quantum Mechanics," Holograph (Folder 21)
  - "A Conversation between Karl R. Popper and Jean-Pierre Vigier," Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Counterexamples to a Proof of Clauser and Horne" (with Thomas D. Angelidis), Typescript (Folder 23)
  - "Determinism and Indeterminism," Holograph outline (Folder 24)
  - "Dismembering (Dismantling) the Philosophy of Meaning," Holograph outline and notes (Folder 25)
  - "Do Ampliative Probabilistic Inferences Exist?" Holograph, n.d. (Folder 26)
  - "The End of Materialism," Holograph outline (Folder 27)
  - Essay volumes, (apparently Projected compilations of selected writings, n.d. 1970s and 1980s).
    - General (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Untitled volumes
      - Preface; Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities; Optimist, Pessimist, and Pragmatist Views of Human Knowledge; Physics and Philosophy; Plato; Historical Explanation (Folder 2)
      - The Bucket and the Searchlight; In Search of Enlightenment; The Status of Science; A Note on the Theory of the Cold War; The Open Society and the Democratic State (Folder 3)
      - Evolutionary Epistemology (Folder 4)
        Includes letter from Gunter Wachtershauser); On the Nutritive Origin of Vision; Remarks on 'Place of Mind in Nature'; The Place of Mind in Nature
      - The Influence of Einstein on My View of Science; Julius Kraft; A Brief Remark on the Theory of the Cold War; A Political Postscript on the Central Problem of the Cold War; The Open Society and the Democratic State (Folder 5)
      - Of Clouds and Clocks; A Realist View of Logic, Physics, and History; Evolution and the Tree of Knowledge; Epistemology Without a Knowing Subject; On the Theory of the Objective Mind; Professor Popper's Seminar On Seeing Red,; The Myth of the Framework; Models, Instruments, and Truth, 1969 January 7 (Folder 6)
      - A Paradox of Zero Information; Extract from Logic without Assumptions; On the Status and the Methods of Science; The Open Society and the Democratic State (Folder 7)
    - "Einstein"
      - Holograph outline and notes (Folder 8)
      - Typescript miscellaneous pages (Folder 9)
    - "Four Essays on Social Philosophy." Notes (Folder 10)
    - "How I See Philosophy"
      - How I See Philosophy (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Indeterminism Is not Enough (Folder 2)
      - Einstein's Influence on My View of Science (Folder 3)
      - The Status of Science: A Broadcast to Russia (Folder 4)
      - Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities; Epistemology and Industrialization; Emancipation Through Knowledge (Folder 5)
      - Creative Self-Criticism in Science and in Art (Folder 6)
    - "In Search of Enlightenment: Essays in the Philosophy of Science and of Politics." Preface; Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities; Optimist, Pessimist, and Pragmatist Views of Scientific Knowledge; Physics and Philosophy; The Bucket and the Searchlight; In Search of Enlightenment; The Status of Science; A Note on the Cold War; The Open Society and the Democratic State; Einstein's Influence on My View of Science; Julius Kraft,; Epistemology and Industrialization; Historical Explanation: An Interview; Models, Instruments, and Truth: The Rationality Principle in the Social Sciences, 1898-1960
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 8)
    - "Lady Popper's Essay Volume"
      - Philosophy and Physics (Folder 9)
      - The Revolution in Our Idea of Knowledge (Folder 10)
    - "The Myth of the Framework" (also entitled "Emancipation through Knowledge" and "On History and Society")
      - General
        - Notes and table of contents (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence (Folder 2)
        - Working copy (Folder 3)
      - Emancipation through Knowledge (Folder 4-5)
      - The Myth of the Framework (Folder 6-8)
      - The Pluralist Approach to the Philosophy of History (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - Epistemology and Industrialization (Folder 3-4)
      - Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities (Folder 5-6)
      - The Moral Responsibility of the Scientist (Folder 7-8)
      - Models, Instruments and Truth (Folder 9)
      - The Logic of the Social Sciences (Folder 10)
      - Reason or Revolution (Folder 11)
      - The Frankfurt School (Folder 12)
      - The Rationality of Scientific Revolutions (Folder 13)
    - "Philosophy and Physics" (also entitled "Realism and Physics")
      - General (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Notes
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Dictated to Jeremy F. G. Shearmur (Folder 3)
      - Correspondence. (Folder 4)
        Includes queries and suggestions
      - Tables of contents (Folder 5)
      - Preface (Folder 6)
      - Philosophy and Physics (Folder 7-12)
      - Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities (Folder 13-14)
      - Quantum Mechanics without 'The Observer' (Folder 15-19)
      - The Propensity Interpretation of the Calculus of Probability, and the Quantum Theory (Folder 20-23)
      - The Propensity Interpretation of Probability (Folder 24-26)
      - Particle Annihilation and the Argument of Einstein, Podolsky and Rosen (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
      - Quantum Theory, Quantum Logic and the Calculus of Probability (Folder 5-7)
      - Birkhoff and von Neumann's Interpretation of Quantum Mechanics (Folder 8-10)
      - Indeterminism in Quantum Physics and in Classical Physics (Folder 11-13)
      - On the Objectivity of the Arrow of Time and the Current Theory of Entropy (Folder 14-15)
      - Time, Probability and Indeterminism (Folder 16-17)
      - Discussion Remarks from a Symposium (Folder 18-19)
      - Normal Science and Its Dangers (Folder 20)
      - The Moral Responsibility of the Scientist (Folder 21-22)
      - Appendices: On the Probabilistic Theory of Induction. Probability Magic or Knowledge out of Ignorance; On Carnap's Version of Laplace's Rule of Succession; The Mysteries of Udolpho: A Reply to Professors Jeffrey and Bar-Hillel; A Comment on Miller's New Paradox of Information; A Paradox of Zero Information; On Rules of Detachment and So-Called Inductive Logic; Theories, Experience, and Probabilistic Intuitions; Creative and Non-Creative Definitions in the Calculus of Probability (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
      - Bibliography (Folder 4)
    - "A Pluralist Approach to (the Philosophy of) History." Theories of Knowledge: The Bucket and the Searchlight; Three Idols of Empiricism: Precision - Definition - The Senses and Their Data; A Pluralist Approach to the Philosophy of History; Eine objektive Theorie des historischen Verstehens; Historical Explanation; Die Logik der Sozialwissenschaften; Models, Instruments, and Truth; Epistemology and Industrialisation; In Search of Enlightenment; The Status of Science; The Open Society and the Democratic State; A Note on the Cold War; Reason or Revolution. Outline for a suggested volume sent to Arne F. Petersen on, 1971 May 21 (Folder 5)
    - "Social Science/Social Philosophy" (also entitled "Philosophy of Science and of Politics")
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Historical Explanation (Folder 7)
      - Julius Kraft (Folder 8)
      - Optimist, Pessimist, and Pragmatist Views of Scientific Knowledge (Folder 9)
      - A Note on the Cold War (Folder 10)
      - The Open Society and the Democratic State (Folder 11)
    - "Wie ich die Philosophie sehe" (intended for publication in Reclam ). Das Sokratische Nichtwissen; Wie Ich die Philosophie sehe; Wissenschaft und Kritik; Der Einfluss philosophischer Probleme auf die Physik der Materie; Wissenschaftliche Reduktion und die essentielle Unvollstandigkeit der Wissenschaft; Die Rationalitat wissenschaftlicher Revolutionen; Der relativistische Mythos; Woran glaubt der Westen?; Utopie und Gewalt; Selbstbefreiung durch das Wissen
      - Typescript (Folder 12)
      - Proofs (Folder 13)
  - "Ethical and Methodological Individualism," (probably 1960s or early 1970s). Speech given in the United States. Typescript (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Explanation and Prediction," Speech. Holograph and typescript (also entitled "Natural Laws and Theoretical Systems" and "Laws of Nature and Theoretical Methods") (Folder 2)
  - "Extensionality," (probably 1940s). See also Notes while developing a theory of natural deduction, n.d.
    - "Extensionality in a Rudimentary Boolean Algebra" (Paper No. 1). Notes, outlines, and typescript (Folder 3)
    - "Completeness and Extensionality of a Rudimentary Boolean Algebra" (Paper No. 2). Notes and typescript (Folder 4)
    - "Postulates for Boolean Algebra" (Paper No. 3). Notes and typescript (Folder 5)
  - Foreword to unidentified book, Holograph (in German), n.d. (Folder 6)
  - "A Formal Proof that Universal Laws of Nature Have Zero Probability," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "Francis Bacon's Theory of Science," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "Freedom and Truth," Speech fragment. Holograph and typescript (Folder 9)
  - "A General Theory of Inference," Holograph., n.d. (Folder 10)
    Includes notes on interpretations
  - "'Gewohnheit' und 'Gesetzerlebnis' in der Erziehung: Eine Padagogisch-strukturpsychologische Monographie," Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "Historicism and the Treason of the Intellect," Holograph (Folder 12)
  - "Hypothesis and Confirmation: Fundamentals of Scientific Research," Typescript (translated by J. H. Woodger) (Folder 13)
  - "The Idea of an Ampliative Probabilistic Inference," Holograph outline, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "The Illusion of Probabilistic Induction," Holograph (Folder 15)
  - "In Defense of Classical Physics," Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Induction," Holograph notes (Folder 17)
  - "The Inquiring Mind," Typescript outline (Folder 18)
  - "The Insignificance of Definitions," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - "The Interpretation of Bell's Inequality and of the Aspect's Experiments," Holograph (Folder 20)
  - "Is the Human Will Free?" Holograph, n.d. (Folder 21)
  - "Is there a Quantum Logic?" Holograph, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - "Joske's Two Problems," Typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Knowledge Without Belief," Typescript speech, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "The Left-Hand Side of the Clauser and Horne Inequality: An Attempt to Localize a Mistake," Holograph (Folder 3)
  - "Library," Holograph notes, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "Logic Derivations," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Natural Deduction and Sheffer Strokes," Holograph (Folder 6)
  - "A New Axiomatization of Probability," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "A New Basis for General Semantics and General Syntax," Holograph. (Folder 8)
    Includes a footnote about semantical categories
  - "A New Model for One Mind-Body Problem," Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Nichtwissen, Glaube, und Hoffnung," Holograph (Folder 10)
  - "Niels Bohr," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "A Note on Carnap's 'Formalization of Logic'," Holograph notes and typescript. (Folder 12)
    Includes notes entitled "Generalized Lattices and Modal Logic"
  - "A Note on Evolution," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "A Note on Four Interpretations of the Quantum Formalism," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "A Note on Inductivism and the Ceteris Paribus Clause," Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Note on Schrodinger for Irreversibility Paper," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Notes, (approximate dates given when known). Holograph unless otherwise stated, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 17-23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 459, Folder 3)
    - On Sigmund Freud (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - On Germany and nuclear war, after Typescript, 1979. (Folder 25)
    - On induction (Folder 26)
    - On memory (Folder 27)
    - On prime numbers (Folder 28)
    - On probability (and induction) (Folder 29-34)
    - On the probability calculus (and induction), 1980s. (Folder 35)
      Includes two versions of holograph fragment
    - On Putnam's analogy thesis and on the Haldane argument (Folder 36)
    - On rationality. (Folder 37)
      Includes translation by Karl Popper of part of Paul Bernays' letter of 1975 January 27
    - On realism (Folder 38)
    - On time (Folder 39)
    - On the work of Carnap or Tarski (Folder 40)
    - While developing a theory of natural deduction, Holograph and typescript notes and fragments. This material eventually went into the following publications: "Why are the Calculuses of Logic and Arithmetic Applicable to Reality?" "New Foundations for Logic," "Logic without Assumptions," "Functional Logic without Axioms or Primitive Rules of Inference," "On the Theory of Deduction," and "The Trivialization of Mathematical Logic", 1940s. (Folder 41)
  - "Objective and Subjective Probability," Typescript (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "On a Crucial Form of the Original Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen Experiment," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "On Probability and Induction," Holograph (Folder 3)
  - "On Relative Logic," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "On Some Measures of Independence," Holograph (Folder 5)
  - "On the Descriptive Function of Language," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - "On the Impossibility of Universal Induction," Notes, holograph, and typescript (Folder 7)
  - "On the Logic of Negation," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "On the Logic of Quantum Mechanics," Notes and holograph (Folder 9)
  - "On the Power of the Probability Calculus to Solve the Problem of Induction,"
    - Holograph (Folder 10)
    - Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "On the Relation of Explanation to Description," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - "On the Role of Critical Arguments in Science and in Philosophy," Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "On the So-Called Rule of Succession," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "On the Symmetry and Consistency of the Special Theory of Relativity," Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "On the Theory of almost Rabid Inference, or p(a,b) = 1," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - "The Origin of the Subjectivist Interpretation of the Mathematical Theory of Probability," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - "Philosophical Analysis and the Economic Relation," Typescript (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Philosophie," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "Philosophy and the Sciences," Holograph (Folder 3)
  - "Philosophy, Science, and Art," Notes and incomplete typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Physical Theory of the Nothing," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Pluralism in Physics: A Pluralistic Universe," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - "Postscript to Ulrich Hoger's Article," Holograph., n.d. (Folder 7)
    Includes Ulrich Hoger's article, entitled "Statistical Foundations of Wave-Mechanics"
  - "Pragmatism vs. Theoreticism," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "The Present Problem of Knowledge," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - "Probabilistic Independence and Confirmation or Corroboration: Reply to the Preceding Note" (originally entitled "Probability and Confirmation or Corroboration: Answer to Preceding Note"), Holograph and typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Probabilistic Independence and Corroboration by Empirical Tests," Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "Probability, Causation, and So-Called Subjunctive Conditionals," Holograph and typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Probability of a Theory," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "The Probability of Laws and the Laws of Probability," Holograph (Folder 14)
  - "The Problem of Inductive Support," Holograph (Folder 15)
  - "The Problem of Superposition - of the Phase," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - "Problems, Insoluble and Soluble," Notes and outlines. See also "Philosophy and the Sciences" and "Structure and Status of Scientific Theories" (Folder 17)
  - "Proof of Euclid's Theorem 'There Does Not Exist a Greatest Prime Number'," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - "Die Prufbarkeit von statistischen Hypothesen," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - "Pure Science: Its Motives and Objectives," Broadcast conversation with Professor P. Percival. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Quantum Theory and Action at a Distance," Holograph (Folder 21)
  - "Radical Nominalism," Notes, holograph, and typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Raum und Zeit," Holograph (Folder 23)
  - "Reason, Freedom, and Society," Speech. Notes, holograph, and typescript (Folder 24)
  - "A Refutation of Determinism,", n.d.
    - Notes (Folder 25)
    - Holograph (in part typescript) (Folder 26-29)
    - Typescript (in part holograph) (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - "A Refutation of Idealism, Phenomenalism, and Positivism," Speech, Moral Sciences Club, Cambridge, England. Holograph (Folder 3)
  - "Relative Theory of Systems," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "A Remark on Carnap's Version of Laplace's Rule of Succession," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Remarks made in a discussion of an address by Willard Van Orman Quine, Typescript, n.d. (Box 459, Folder 4)
  - "Revolution and Continuity in Science," Typescript (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "La Science est-elle un bien public?" Typescript speech, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "The Sciences Natural and Physical: What Is Science?" Typescript speech (Folder 8)
  - "Seeing Red," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - "Shortest Absolutely Random Sequences," Holograph (Folder 10)
  - "Significance and Limits of Demarcation," Holograph outline (Folder 11)
  - "The Significance of the Reflexive Paradoxes," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - "Simply Independent Postulates for Boolean Algebra" (Paper No. 1), Notes and typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Some Comments on Truth and the Growth of Knowledge," Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Some Fundamental Problems of the Theory of Probability," Three lectures held at the Imperial College, London, England. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Some Remarks on Recent Philosophy," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Speech in defense of science and mathematics, and against the attack on "the great tradition," Holograph (in German) (Folder 17)
  - Speech on the history of some problems of physics, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Speech on the philosophy of science (within the framework of a course entitled "Recent Developments in Contemporary British Philosophy"), Typescript, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - Speech on the probability calculus, (probably 1980s). Holograph of first two paragraphs, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Speech on the theory of knowledge and on the philosophy of history, Typed transcript (Folder 21)
  - Speech on various theories of artistic creativity, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - "A Statistical Experiment to Determine the Michelsonian Ether-Drift," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - "The Status of the Principle of Equivalence and of Mach's Principle in General Relativity," Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "Structure and Status of Scientific Theories," Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Three (Complexes of) Ideas of Political Philosophy," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 26)